Martin Kamin Papers
Martin Kamin Papers
- Writings
  - By others
    - Reyna, Fernando, Encyclopedie du Ballet, complete book, in French; typescript; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Rundy, W. H., Mareska: The Tsigane, 1917; composition book containing text of play; handwritten, green and red pencil (Box 33)
    - Salazar, Adolfo, Concerning the Dance [ Sinfonia y ballet], English translation, partial; typescript (Box 33)
    - Sandoz, Maurice, See also Writings by others: Armstrong, Ronald.
      - Correspondence with, 1954-1958; letters to and from the Kamins regarding Sandoz' books (Box 34)
      - Correspondence about, 1955-1959; various issues relating to illustration, printing and publication of several of Sandoz' books; includes John Lewinsky, Tillie Stiller, Evelyn Hofer (photographer), printers, binders, etc. (Box 34)
      - Photographs of, portrait, two sheets of contact prints (Box 34)
        See also Writings by others: Armstrong, Ronald
      - Diaghilev, Nijinsky, and Other Vignettes, commentary by Romola Nijinska (typescript), introduction by Walter Terry (typescript), photographs, publicity, reviews and responses from notable figures in the dance world, miscellaneous material related to production of book; 5 folders (Box 34)
      - Pleasures of Mexico, pgotographs, publicity, original typescript in Spanish, miscellaneous material related to production of book; 4 folders (Box 34)
        See also Writings by others: Armstrong, Ronald; Armstrong wrote the preface for this book
    - Schnitzler, Arthur, The Green Cockatoo, excerpt of play; typescript (Box 34)
    - Schwezoff, Igor, "Thoughts on ballet", essay; typescript (Box 34)
    - Seldes, George, The Great Quotations, introduction and a few sections from book; typescript (Box 34)
    - Stockbridge, Dorothy, Jezebel, excerpt of play; typescript (Box 34)
    - Towne, Jackson Edmund, Princess Cholula, one-act play about the conquest of Mexico; typescript carbon (Box 34)
    - Vermilye, Theodore, "Sanctity vs Communism", essay; typescript (Box 34)
    - de Warren, Robert and Jacqueline, "Balletphone", proposal for course in ballet appreciation; typescript carbon (Box 34)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Articles, various authors, 2 folders (Box 35)
        Typescripts of thirty-two articles that appeared in the magazines Controversy and New Controversy. The first folder contains a complete list of titles and authors.
      - Ballet scenarios, unidentified authors (Box 35)
        Typed summaries or scenarios for the following: The red mask; The birthday of the Infanta; The flower ballet; several adaptations of Hans Christian Anderson fairy tales; Christmas shop windows; The rivals; Mandragora; The tragedy of the cello; Perseus; Volma's memories (Памяи А. Р. Волъма, in Russian)
      - Books, unidentified authors (Box 35)
        Chapter summary and notes for book on an invented language, "Rawson Universal"
      - Essays, unidentified authors (Box 35)
        Typescripts of six essays: The ballet theatre in New York, 1940; Introduction to book on Haitian folklore and dance; Life in Chicago en famille (name at end is "Bobbie-Celeste"); Literature of the dance; The one two three of Harriet Schonberg (includes photograph); Prospectus for world news association; Theodore Komisarjevsky
      - Scripts, unidentified authors (Box 35)
        Typed excerpts from The Acid Test, The Wife, and an unidentified play about Cleopatra.
      - Notes and fragments (Box 35)
        Notes on various topics, in several differents hands, in English, French and other languages